Hello world. Today, we're going to
explore some of the ins and outs of gun
ownership in Japan. Like, if one were to
want to hunt hair using guns, what sort
of licenses do they need to acquire? Can
you even touch a gun without a gun
license? Where do you even go to buy a
firearm? How are you supposed to keep
firearms and ammunition safely tucked
away? All of these questions will be
answered and more as we take a look into
an American hunter's community in
Okayama, Japan. Meet Dave. He's what a
lot of expats in my generation like to
call a lifer. Someone that's made Japan
their long-term home, maybe with a
family, house, and career set here for
the foreseeable future. He's a friend of
Bobby's, our part-time producer, and was
kind enough to share his experience and
knowledge for all of us to enjoy. So,
without further ado, let's hear from
Dave about how one even begins to
legally own a gun in Japan.
>> So, this is my actual gun license.
So, the way
uh a gun license works in Japan is that
there's a license,
a person, and a gun, and all three of
those things are connected. So, only I
can own this gun.
Only I can use this gun, and
uh
this gun license is only for me. The
first step is you go to a several
hour-long seminar run by the police, and
at the end of that, there's a
50-question
true and false test, and you have to
score 90% or above uh to pass that. The
test itself is really difficult. It's 50
questions true or false, which sounds
easy, but uh it's all in Japanese, and
it's all written in kind of legalese.
So, it's not even just uh standard
Japanese. It's It's very formal
uh legal legal-sounding terms for
everything. And, you know, just one
small difference in the the way the
question is written could easily make it
true or false. Um so I I studied really
hard for months. I was in a classroom
full of 30 or 40 people and maybe only
about half of the people in the room
passed the test actually.
Once you pass the paper test, uh the
next thing you have to do is schedule
time to go to a gun range where a
professional will teach you how to
handle the gun and how to shoot the gun.
Uh so you have to remember that stage of
the process for 99% of Japanese people
will be the first time that they ever
touch a real gun. So it's very basic and
it's
uh mostly safety oriented. It's not
really about becoming a great shooter on
the first day. It's more about handling
the gun in a safe manner. And uh you
need things like you need a doctor to
give you a mental uh health certificate.
There's a lot of um background
information that you have to give to the
police. So your employment history, uh
the history of the addresses that you've
lived at recently,
uh and then the police will come out and
talk to everybody you know. They'll talk
to your family, they'll talk to your
boss, they'll talk to your neighbors. So
there's steps within steps of this
process.
>> And Dave's not kidding. There are well
over a dozen steps to getting your gun
license and owning a gun in Japan. We've
listed here what we think is a pretty
comprehensive list of to-dos, but don't
take our word for it. Make sure to
consult with your local police and
hunting organizations. And I'm sure that
a lot of you are wondering just how much
all of this cost the average applicant.
Well, according to this spreadsheet that
Dave provided, by adding up all of the
test, certificate, ammunition, gun, and
miscellaneous costs together, he spent
332,725
yen, or about 2,100 US dollars, to get
started as a hunter in Japan. That's
actually less than my Sony a7s III.
Anyway, let's get back to Dave where
he'll show us what his gun locker looks
like.
>> So,
we keep the locker back here.
Uh so, according to Japanese law,
uh the gun locker and the ammunition
locker have to be in separate places. In
my case, they're actually in separate
buildings.
Uh another part of the law is that only
I can possess the key to the locker and
not even any of my family members can
even know where I keep this key,
actually. So,
and uh as you can see, it's not the same
as like a gun safe as uh people in
Europe or North America might think of
it. It's more like a uh a school locker
type uh toughness of uh of a material,
but it is connected to the wall, so
nobody can just pick the whole thing up
and take it.
And uh if you take a look inside,
so, this is the way that we are supposed
to store our guns. Uh if if possible,
we're supposed to take the barrel off
and store it separately, and then the
body of the gun actually has one more
the uh magnet stuck to there.
>> [laughter]
>> Wow.
>> Uh if you look inside here, this is the
way guns are supposed to be stored. Uh
ideally, the barrel is supposed to be
disconnected from the main body of the
gun, and then the main body of the gun
has one more chain and lock through it,
so there's two locks of protection.
So, when you initially get your gun
license,
uh before before you have your
permission to buy your first gun,
you have to have the gun locker and
ammunition locker installed, and they
come and check to make sure that you
have that.
And then, they will finally give you
permission to buy your first gun.
Uh
every 3 years, you have to renew your
gun license.
And at that time, they come out and they
look again just to make sure that
everything is still installed correctly.
So, normally, uh only I can handle this
gun. Uh
other people, even if they have a gun
license, they're not allowed to handle
this gun or shoot this gun or go hunting
with this gun. But, a gunshop is one of
the few places where you can go in Japan
and actually touch a lot of different uh
guns uh while you're choosing the the
gun that you're going to buy. Of course,
uh you can you can hold them and try
them out. You can't shoot them,
but at least you can handle them.
Uh so, I went to a gunshop and picked
out the the first gun that I wanted.
And then, the gunshop themselves have to
fill out a lot of paperwork and send
that to the police. And then, at the
same time, I fill out separate paperwork
saying, uh this is the gun this is the
specific gun
that I would like to purchase.
And uh then, the police will make their
decision whether you're allowed to buy
that or not. In between, there's another
step which is uh another application
process where you have to apply for
permission to buy ammunition.
So, uh
that's just another uh part that's like
in the back of the license. Uh uh uh uh
uh uh uh uh uh uh uh uh
So, like here's my my current permission
to buy and own and store and use
ammunition. And this is good for like 1
year. Uh uh uh
Actually, if it runs out, I can still
use it and own it. I just couldn't buy
any more. So, every year, uh I have to
reapply for for this if I want to buy
new ammunition.
Um after that, then finally, you can go
to a shooting range uh in this area.
There's two, and if you drive a few
hours away up north or out west, there's
a few more that you can go to, but
they're a little bit few and far
between. They're usually way out in the
middle of nowhere, so that the noise
doesn't bother people.
And then all shooting ranges in Japan
are either skeet or trap ranges, which
are two different kinds of
clay pigeon shooting. There's also rifle
ranges, so once you can finally own a
rifle,
you can shoot like a 50 m or 100 m
range.
>> So where are we today, Dave? Where are
we going?
>> So we're at the Okayama Clay Shooting
Range in Mitsu. So it's about 45 minutes
north of Okayama City. Today, we're
going to meet the rest of the Minami
Bunkai
part of the Okayama Hunting Association
group, and we're going to do some target
shooting to get ready for the hunting
season.
So there's two stations for trap
shooting and two stations for skeet
shooting.
Like I have another shooting vest,
but just like you can wear whatever you
want as a shooting vest. I mean, the the
main purpose of a shooting vest is just
have big pockets to put all the shells
in.
>> [laughter]
>> That's the main purpose of it.
Otherwise, it's hard to carry the shells
around.
But we wear this when we go out hunting
for safety, but then because this is a
hunting group practice, we just wear
this because,
you know, it's the group it's the group
identifier.
If that makes sense.
As long as you're like behind us, you
can kind of float around until somebody
tells you, "Hey, you're not supposed to
stand in this area." But, yeah.
Cuz we'll move around the semicircle.
So,
when you're out hunting, it doesn't
matter, but at the shooting range, you
just want to like close it quietly so
that it doesn't activate the the
the clays to fire.
And then whenever you're not shooting,
you just want to make sure that the
chamber is open, and then that way you
know that the gun's not loaded and it's
safe to put down.
So, these headphones are electronic. So,
of course, they have a lot of padding
that just blocks the sound, but they
also have a microphone on the front. So,
if someone is talking to me, I can hear
them talk. However, when a gunshot goes
off, the
internal speaker automatically cuts off
so that you don't get any of that
gunshot sound
coming through the speaker into your
ear, and you have the natural pattern
sound reduction. So, it's quite nice
because you can have conversations with
people without having to take your ear
protection on and off constantly, but
you know you're fully protected from
gunshot sound. Pull.
If I hit more than half on skeet, I'm
usually pretty happy with my
performance, so I'm I'm quite happy with
out of 25.
Pull.
Like whenever we register for hunting
season, it's kind of all folded in
together. So, it's like your hunting
association dues, the registration fee
that goes to the government, and
insurance. So, that's like special
insurance that covers you in the hunting
season.
That's all pulled it up into sort of one
one payment that we make.
And I think it's 34,000 yen, something
like that.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh you know, even at the shooting range,
you can't try out your friends' guns.
You you can't even pick up and and look
down the sights of your friends' guns.
Uh so, it's it's very strict, which
makes it very hard to select a gun. Uh
especially, I had little to no gun
experience
uh previous to this. Had only been to
firing ranges a few times in my life.
Uh so, yeah. So, without shooting this
gun, I had to uh purchase it and and
hope for the best that it was going to
be a good fit for me.
Uh the first gun I got was this Beretta,
and I bought this used. These are both
uh 12-gauge shotguns. Um in Japan,
uh the first 10 years that you own a
gun, you can only own a shotgun.
Uh that could generally be uh 12-gauge
or 20-gauge shotgun. After 10 years, if
you
have done everything
uh legally and lawfully, then you can
ask for permission to own a hunting
rifle.
Uh there's only two reasons to own guns
in Japan. And that is for target
shooting, and the other reason is
hunting. So, the basic thinking is that
a shotgun is a kind of an all-around
kind of weapon that can handle
uh any of those hunting tasks.
So, it's good for people who only want
to do sport shooting, and it's also
basically
what you need to start hunting. If you
compare uh a rifle to a shotgun,
a rifle can shoot much, much further,
probably three to five times further
than a shotgun can.
Japan is very hilly and wooded and
crowded. Uh so, unless you're somewhere
like the wilds of Hokkaido, you're very
rarely trying to shoot at a deer or boar
that's 2 or 300 m away from you. Uh
usually you're shooting everything
within 100 m of where you are.
So, you don't necessarily need a super
high-powered uh hunting rifle for that
kind of task. And especially as a
beginner, it's just safer to
have a shotgun that you can't
accidentally shoot like over a hill or
much further than you intended to shoot
it. So, it's a little safer to start out
with and it can do everything that you
need it to do. So, the gun license and
hunting license are separate. You need
to take tests to uh get both of those.
Um the gun license is uh run and
controlled by the police.
And the hunting license is run and
controlled by the uh
uh Ministry of Land and Forests,
basically.
Uh these badges here, uh each year when
uh you register officially to hunt, uh
you get a metal badge that you have to
either display like on your hunting vest
or on your hat.
Uh and each prefecture has a a different
badge. So, you have to register and pay
in each pre- prefecture that you want to
hunt in. The hunting season in Japan is
November 15th to February 15th. There
are some exceptions to that. I think it
starts a little bit earlier in Hokkaido,
but most of the other prefectures, it's
the middle of November to the middle of
February.
Now, uh where I live in Okayama
Prefecture, there's an overpopulation
of deer and boar. So, just that 3-month
hunting season is not enough to control
the population uh
well enough. So, there's a 1-month uh
extension uh for the past few years
from February 15th until March 15th that
is only for deer and boar. And there's
different kinds of hunting in Japan. So,
there's gun hunting.
And then, you can also use it like an
air gun, like a pellet gun or an air
gun.
And there's also trapping, which is
actually probably more popular and uh
gets a lot more animals than gun hunting
does. So, trapping is also very popular.
Outside of the regular hunting season uh
for experienced hunters, there's also um
special permission for hunters to hunt
year-round uh just to keep the number of
pest animals down.
Uh I don't have any experience hunting
in the US um
but from what I understand, a lot of
hunting in the US is kind of go out in
the woods and, you know, find your spot
and settle down and wait.
Whereas, a lot of hunting in Japan is
trying to drive the animals uh into the
group of hunters. So, for example, uh
when I go boar hunting
uh we have anywhere between 10 and 15
hunters
and
uh two to four dogs.
So, what will happen is we'll we'll go
out to the countryside and we all spread
out uh around one side of a mountain,
basically.
But spread out means uh so far spread
out that you you don't see the next
person.
You know, you're several hundred meters
to the next person at the closest.
And then, the dogs will be released on
the far side of the mountain.
And hopefully, if everything goes right,
they will drive the boar into the the
line of hunters uh on the other side of
the mountain. And it's the same very
similar with uh deer hunting in that
respect. Cuz you can go out all day boar
hunting or deer hunting, and even if the
group gets three boar,
like that might not be me. So, there
could be like literally nothing to film
except for me standing staring at a
patch of woods.
But, the duck hunting is always
action-packed and like I definitely
recommend that
for good footage.
Okay, so the way duck hunting uh works
that we do around here,
we can edit that part out later. Uh so,
the way duck hunting usually works uh
when I go, it's called jump hunting. So,
uh we go
So, we go to an area of low hills where
there are many ponds up in the tops of
valleys.
Uh those ponds used to be the irrigation
ponds that uh fed the rice fields. Uh
nowadays, nobody uses those because they
use irrigation pumps. Uh
but, the ponds are all still there, and
a lot of them are overgrown
uh all around the edges with trees. So,
this is the perfect place for ducks to
sleep.
The ducks like to sleep on the water and
be protected by the tree branches
overhead.
So, what we do is we try to drive nearby
the ponds and park, and then the final
100 m we creep up to the edge of the
pond, and
uh hopefully all the hunters kind of pop
up over the edge of the pond at the same
time. And if there's ducks there, then
uh we take our shots.
So, we will go around to like a series
of 10 or 12 ponds throughout one
morning. Uh we you can't
um
you can't hunt until the legal sunrise.
Uh so, I think today that's like 6:35
a.m., something like that. So, we'll try
to be out at the first pond by that
time. And then we'll go for a couple
hours. So, we just drive around from
pond to pond.
That's right. So, today's official
sunrise is 6:37 a.m., which is
in 7 minutes.
So, we're going to hang out till then.
>> [groaning]
>> [__]
Come here.
So, we hit a few.
One landed in a really good easy to take
spot.
The one I hit landed down the hill and
there's like one more somewhere over
there that they're going to look for
with the dog.
So here when you get a duck the first
thing to do is you take its guts out
and then the meat won't spoil.
And then uh
you can let it you know you just put it
in a in the car in a bag and it it can
just wait until the end of the hunt to
take care of it
once you take the intestines out.
So [clears throat] I don't know why we
lined up in that order because the first
two ladies hadn't been with this group
before so they didn't know what to do.
They're supposed to run out
to the very end and then let everybody
line up
but they didn't go fast enough and
that's why I just ran past them. So
otherwise everyone like this like a
traffic jam and everyone can't get out
to where they can shoot.
But they they should have had
uh
someone who's been with our group a
bunch of times to run out first. But
they're I think they're being polite
like oh and these people you should go
first but they didn't know what to do.
It's always like that on the first day.
I mean we're going to go to like 10
ponds today so it's
no big deal.
>> So about that, we visited several more
ponds that day but none of them had
ducks that were legal to shoot. So the
most action packed footage of duck
hunting is uh what you just saw. But on
a bright note we did get to hear from
some of Dave's hunting buddies about
their experiences as hunters.
>> [laughter]
>> I got into it at the urging of a friend,
but it's also something that
my grandfather and my uncles
are really into and um
I would always had a little bit of
interest in the back of my mind to do
it, uh but I I moved to Japan when I was
in my early 20s, so I never
never really had a chance to do it when
I was an adult out of my own in America.
So, I just thought, "Oh, this is a good
chance." And I like the outdoors. Like,
I'm actually into hiking and camping,
outdoor activities. I think it's it's
fun and interesting. And it's
a kind of a difficult [clears throat]
hobby just because it's it's very
technical and there's
a lot of things to learn.
But, at the same time, I've really met a
super group of people who have been
teaching me things. I still have I've
I've hunted for three seasons now. So, I
wouldn't say I'm an expert hunter by any
stretch of the imagination. But, I'm
definitely learning things all the time.
And even when you are able to get an
animal, there's still a huge process
after that. Which, you know, involves
preparing the animal, you know, into
into meat ready to eat. So, even after
you get a deer or a boar, there's
there's still a lot of things to do.
>> So, the head of the hunting community
that Dave is a part of, Nieda-san, owns
a meat processing facility in the
outskirts of the city. The facility
meets health code regulations, and so
Nieda-san processes and sells wild meats
to clients across the country. Several
times a year, members of this group will
gather to socialize, eat, and do some
maintenance on the facility grounds.
Every member pitches in a certain amount
of money each year to help fund fishing
outings in the Sea of Japan, barbecues,
and other excursions. It's a community
that, throughout all my years in
Okinawa, I had never gotten to see
before. So, while I could imagine vegans
and vegetarians being incredibly
uncomfortable there, for me, it was an
interesting and novel experience.
>> Far as I know, in this prefecture, I'm
the only foreigner that owns a a gun.
Now, there are places in Japan with a
lot more foreigners with guns.
Uh for example, Yamaguchi Prefecture is
close to the Iwakuni
uh Marine Base. From what I have heard
from people, there are tons of uh US
service members who are very into
hunting, who get their permission to own
guns in Japan and go hunting. So, at at
first when I started to get into all of
this and and studying for my test, I
thought, "Wow, this is so
uh strict and regulated."
And and I thought, "Oh, it can't really
possibly be like this in America."
Uh it must be, you know, the image of
America is that it's pretty easy to get
a gun and use a gun. But actually, when
I started to look into the laws in
America around uh gun ownership and
hunting,
they're not that different, actually. Um
I mean, if you want to talk about like
owning pistols or something in America,
that's a kind of a totally different
category. But as far as like owning
firearms for hunting, um
other than the obvious restriction of of
not being able to own a rifle right
away, um
the laws are very similar, you know? And
they're they're designed uh
for safety.
And uh as far as I know, there's very
few hunting accidents in Japan, even
though they they probably do happen
every once in a while. So, the focus is
on safety and the focus is on uh keeping
your weapons secure even when you're not
using them.
But I don't really, you know, I don't
disagree with how hard it is to get a
gun because all of the red tape just you
basically you're just proving that
you're motivated to do it. You have a
real reason and that you're going to be
a responsible gun owner.
>> And while we're on the topic of gun
safety, here's a chart showing
gun-related fatality data from the
United States, Canada, Australia, and
Japan. I recommend taking this
information with a grain of salt and
doing your own research, too. But from
what we could find, there have been no
gun-related deaths among hunters in
Japan in the past several years. Both
Japan and Australia are known for their
strict gun laws, so this may come as no
surprise to you, but the number of
gun-related fatalities in the United
States is much, much higher than in
these two countries. We may make an
entire video focused on guns and public
safety somewhere down the line, but for
now I just wanted to include some basic
information for any of you who may be
curious.
Anyway, that's it for our video on gun
laws in Japan. A big and his friends for
being so helpful for the production of
this video. Happy hunting everyone.
Thanks for watching. See you next time.
Peace.
What's owning a gun like where you're
from?